{
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "When did Louis XIV begin to centralize authority in France and its holdings?",
            "options": [
                "1650s",
                "1660s",
                "1670s",
                "1680s"
            ],
            "answer": "1660s",
            "id": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary religion of the homogeneous population established in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Protestant",
                "Catholic",
                "Anglican",
                "Orthodox"
            ],
            "answer": "Catholic",
            "id": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "By what year did New France reach its peak expansion from Newfoundland to the Rocky Mountains?",
            "options": [
                "1712",
                "1701",
                "1720",
                "1750"
            ],
            "answer": "1712",
            "id": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary geographical feature of Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "Mountains",
                "Plains",
                "Lakes",
                "Water bodies"
            ],
            "answer": "Water bodies",
            "id": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European power enjoyed a significant advantage in the Atlantic fisheries due to the Azores?",
            "options": [
                "Spain",
                "Portugal",
                "France",
                "Great Britain"
            ],
            "answer": "Portugal",
            "id": 4
        },
        {
            "question": "What year marks the founding of Port-Royal in Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "1604",
                "1605",
                "1606",
                "1607"
            ],
            "answer": "1605",
            "id": 5
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Anglicized version of the name 'Acadiens'?",
            "options": [
                "Arcadians",
                "Acadians",
                "Cajuns",
                "Canadiens"
            ],
            "answer": "Acadians",
            "id": 6
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the French term for the Acadian Expulsion?",
            "options": [
                "Le Grand Exil",
                "Le Grand Voyage",
                "Le Grand D\u00e9rangement",
                "Le Grand D\u00e9part"
            ],
            "answer": "Le Grand D\u00e9rangement",
            "id": 7
        },
        {
            "question": "From which region of France did the first settlers of Acadia originate?",
            "options": [
                "Normandy",
                "Vienne",
                "Brittany",
                "\u00cele-de-France"
            ],
            "answer": "Vienne",
            "id": 8
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the Catholic governor involved in the Acadien civil war in 1640?",
            "options": [
                "Charles de Menou d\u2019Aulnay de Charnisay",
                "Charles de Saint-\u00c9tienne de la Tour",
                "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "Charles de Menou d\u2019Aulnay de Charnisay",
            "id": 9
        },
        {
            "question": "Which indigenous confederacy was involved in the Acadien civil war?",
            "options": [
                "Iroquois Confederacy",
                "Wabanaki Confederacy",
                "Powhatan Confederacy",
                "Algonquin Confederacy"
            ],
            "answer": "Wabanaki Confederacy",
            "id": 10
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did the British burn Port-Royal to the ground?",
            "options": [
                "1613",
                "1621",
                "1635",
                "1642"
            ],
            "answer": "1613",
            "id": 11
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Acadien settlement was associated with the Protestant governor Charles de Saint-\u00c9tienne de la Tour?",
            "options": [
                "Port-Royal",
                "Saint John",
                "Sable Island",
                "Ste. Croix"
            ],
            "answer": "Saint John",
            "id": 12
        },
        {
            "question": "Who led the defense of La Tour's settlement during d\u2019Aulnay's siege?",
            "options": [
                "Charles de Menou d\u2019Aulnay de Charnisay",
                "Charles de Saint-\u00c9tienne de la Tour",
                "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
            "id": 13
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a primary reason why the Wabanaki Confederacy preferred the French over the English?",
            "options": [
                "Religious affinity",
                "Cultural similarities",
                "The French posed fewer threats",
                "Military alliances"
            ],
            "answer": "The French posed fewer threats",
            "id": 14
        },
        {
            "question": "Which culture in North America is considered to be one of the oldest European-descended cultures?",
            "options": [
                "Cajun",
                "Acadien",
                "French Canadian",
                "British American"
            ],
            "answer": "Acadien",
            "id": 15
        },
        {
            "question": "When did the French first establish a viable presence in Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "1604",
                "1599",
                "1605",
                "1613"
            ],
            "answer": "1605",
            "id": 16
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the territory that became known as Acadia in the 16th century European maps?",
            "options": [
                "Arcadia",
                "L'Acadie",
                "Newfoundland",
                "Port-Royal"
            ],
            "answer": "Arcadia",
            "id": 17
        },
        {
            "question": "Which area did Acadia NOT stretch to?",
            "options": [
                "The south coast of Newfoundland",
                "The Rocky Mountains",
                "New Brunswick",
                "Prince Edward Island"
            ],
            "answer": "The Rocky Mountains",
            "id": 18
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the Anglicized version of 'Acadiens'?",
            "options": [
                "Acadia",
                "Cajuns",
                "L'Acadie",
                "Acadian"
            ],
            "answer": "Acadian",
            "id": 19
        },
        {
            "question": "From which region in France did the first French settlers of Acadia originate?",
            "options": [
                "Vienne",
                "Normandy",
                "Paris",
                "Poitiers"
            ],
            "answer": "Vienne",
            "id": 20
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did a British force from Virginia burn down Port-Royal?",
            "options": [
                "1605",
                "1613",
                "1640",
                "1645"
            ],
            "answer": "1613",
            "id": 21
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the Catholic governor loyal to during the Acadien civil war?",
            "options": [
                "Charles de Menou d\u2019Aulnay de Charnisay",
                "Charles de Saint-\u00c9tienne de la Tour",
                "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
                "Madame La Tour"
            ],
            "answer": "Charles de Menou d\u2019Aulnay de Charnisay",
            "id": 22
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the distance that separated the areas governed by the two competitive governors in Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "23 kilometres",
                "23 miles",
                "30 kilometres",
                "30 miles"
            ],
            "answer": "23 kilometres",
            "id": 23
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of Charles de la Tour\u2019s wife who led the defending troops?",
            "options": [
                "Madame La Tour",
                "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
                "Jacquelin de la Tour",
                "Marie de la Tour"
            ],
            "answer": "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
            "id": 24
        },
        {
            "question": "Which confederacy grafted the Acadiens onto their lives and struggles?",
            "options": [
                "Iroquois Confederacy",
                "Wabanaki Confederacy",
                "Algonquin Confederacy",
                "Huron Confederacy"
            ],
            "answer": "Wabanaki Confederacy",
            "id": 25
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a key reason the Wabanaki Confederacy preferred the French over the English?",
            "options": [
                "Cultural similarities",
                "Military power",
                "French posed fewer threats",
                "Religious reasons"
            ],
            "answer": "French posed fewer threats",
            "id": 26
        },
        {
            "question": "By the late 17th century, many of which indigenous group had converted to Catholicism?",
            "options": [
                "Mi\u2019kmaqs",
                "Maliseet",
                "Abenaki",
                "Penobscot"
            ],
            "answer": "Mi\u2019kmaqs",
            "id": 27
        },
        {
            "question": "What event is known in French as 'Le Grand D\u00e9rangement'?",
            "options": [
                "The Acadian Expulsion",
                "The Acadien Civil War",
                "The French Settlement of Port-Royal",
                "The Burning of Port-Royal"
            ],
            "answer": "The Acadian Expulsion",
            "id": 28
        },
        {
            "question": "What region do the Acadien people in the Maritimes continue to influence?",
            "options": [
                "Regional cultures",
                "European cultures",
                "British Administration",
                "French Settlements"
            ],
            "answer": "Regional cultures",
            "id": 29
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the cultural evolution of the term 'Acadiens' in Louisiana known as?",
            "options": [
                "Cajuns",
                "L'Acadians",
                "Nova Scotians",
                "Creoles"
            ],
            "answer": "Cajuns",
            "id": 30
        },
        {
            "question": "What marked the end of New France's control over its North American territories?",
            "options": [
                "Signing of the Treaty of Utrecht",
                "The French Revolution",
                "The conclusion of the Seven Years' War",
                "The War of Spanish Succession"
            ],
            "answer": "The conclusion of the Seven Years' War",
            "id": 31
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did New France's territory reach its peak expansion?",
            "options": [
                "1605",
                "1712",
                "1763",
                "1620"
            ],
            "answer": "1712",
            "id": 32
        },
        {
            "question": "Which colony was not part of the five colonies that made up New France?",
            "options": [
                "Canada",
                "Acadia",
                "Virginia",
                "Louisiana"
            ],
            "answer": "Virginia",
            "id": 33
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European power did not establish a position in Acadia in the 16th century?",
            "options": [
                "The Dutch",
                "The Portuguese",
                "The British",
                "Both Portuguese and British"
            ],
            "answer": "The Dutch",
            "id": 34
        },
        {
            "question": "Which island chain did the Portuguese use as a stopover en route to the Grand Banks?",
            "options": [
                "The Canary Islands",
                "The Balearic Islands",
                "The Azores",
                "The Madeira Islands"
            ],
            "answer": "The Azores",
            "id": 35
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was Port-Royal founded?",
            "options": [
                "1600",
                "1605",
                "1610",
                "1604"
            ],
            "answer": "1605",
            "id": 36
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the original name given by European maps to the territory that became Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "Arcadia",
                "Nova Scotia",
                "New France",
                "L'Acadie"
            ],
            "answer": "Arcadia",
            "id": 37
        },
        {
            "question": "Which present-day Canadian province was Port-Royal located in?",
            "options": [
                "Quebec",
                "Ontario",
                "Nova Scotia",
                "New Brunswick"
            ],
            "answer": "Nova Scotia",
            "id": 38
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the correct term for the people of Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "Acadien",
                "Acadians",
                "Cajuns",
                "Arcadians"
            ],
            "answer": "Acadiens",
            "id": 39
        },
        {
            "question": "Which term did the deported Acadiens evolve into upon their settlement in Louisiana?",
            "options": [
                "Acadiens",
                "L'Acadiens",
                "Cajuns",
                "Arcadians"
            ],
            "answer": "Cajuns",
            "id": 40
        },
        {
            "question": "From which region of France did the majority of the early settlers of Acadia come?",
            "options": [
                "Normandy",
                "Brittany",
                "Vienne",
                "Burgundy"
            ],
            "answer": "Vienne",
            "id": 41
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the year of the British attack that burned down Port-Royal?",
            "options": [
                "1608",
                "1613",
                "1632",
                "1645"
            ],
            "answer": "1613",
            "id": 42
        },
        {
            "question": "What significant event occurred in 1645?",
            "options": [
                "Founding of Port-Royal",
                "The Acadien Civil War",
                "The siege of Saint John",
                "The Treaty of Utrecht"
            ],
            "answer": "The siege of Saint John",
            "id": 43
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the two competitive governors of Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "Governors d\u2019Aulnay and La Tour",
                "Governors Frontenac and Champlain",
                "Governors Bienville and Iberville",
                "Governors Cartier and Champlain"
            ],
            "answer": "Governors d\u2019Aulnay and La Tour",
            "id": 44
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was known as the 'Lioness of La Tour'?",
            "options": [
                "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
                "Madame La Tour",
                "Anne of Brittany",
                "Jacqueline de la Tour"
            ],
            "answer": "Fran\u00e7oise-Marie Jacquelin",
            "id": 45
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main indigenous confederacy involved with the Acadiens?",
            "options": [
                "The Algonquin Confederacy",
                "The Haudenosaunee Confederacy",
                "The Wabanaki Confederacy",
                "The Confederacy of the Great Lakes"
            ],
            "answer": "The Wabanaki Confederacy",
            "id": 46
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the reason the Wabanaki Confederacy preferred French allies over English?",
            "options": [
                "Religious conversion efforts",
                "Trade agreements",
                "Military alliances",
                "The lesser threat posed by the French"
            ],
            "answer": "The lesser threat posed by the French",
            "id": 47
        },
        {
            "question": "Which indigenous group had many members convert to Catholicism by the late 17th century?",
            "options": [
                "The Mi\u2019kmaq",
                "The Huron",
                "The Cree",
                "The Mohawk"
            ],
            "answer": "The Mi\u2019kmaq",
            "id": 48
        },
        {
            "question": "Which phrase refers to the forced removal of the Acadiens?",
            "options": [
                "The Great Upheaval",
                "The Acadian Exodus",
                "Le Grand D\u00e9rangement",
                "The Big Displacement"
            ],
            "answer": "Le Grand D\u00e9rangement",
            "id": 49
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the modern-day region where Acadien culture remains influential?",
            "options": [
                "The Maritime provinces",
                "The Canadian Shield",
                "The Quebec region",
                "The New England area"
            ],
            "answer": "The Maritime provinces",
            "id": 50
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of support did La Tour seek from New England when his fortunes were slipping?",
            "options": [
                "Military support",
                "Financial support and muscle",
                "Spiritual guidance",
                "Educational resources"
            ],
            "answer": "Financial support and muscle",
            "id": 51
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the rare occurrence in the French Catholic colonies that reflects its religious flexibility?",
            "options": [
                "The appointment of a Protestant governor",
                "The absence of resident priests",
                "Both the appointment of a Protestant governor and the absence of resident priests",
                "Frequent religious congregations"
            ],
            "answer": "Both the appointment of a Protestant governor and the absence of resident priests",
            "id": 52
        },
        {
            "question": "What was Governor d'Aulnay's highest achievement?",
            "options": [
                "Building a large fleet",
                "Draining the salt marshes",
                "Creating an educational system",
                "Establishing a new religion"
            ],
            "answer": "Draining the salt marshes",
            "id": 53
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the outcome of the conflict between d'Aulnay and La Tour?",
            "options": [
                "A permanent state of war",
                "Reconciliation through La Tour's marriage to d'Aulnay's widow",
                "La Tour's execution",
                "The division of Acadia"
            ],
            "answer": "Reconciliation through La Tour's marriage to d'Aulnay's widow",
            "id": 54
        },
        {
            "question": "What made the Fortress of Louisbourg significant?",
            "options": [
                "It was the first station to use radio",
                "It was located on \u00cele Royale, built in 1713",
                "It was built entirely by the Acadiens",
                "It never saw conflict"
            ],
            "answer": "It was located on \u00cele Royale, built in 1713",
            "id": 55
        },
        {
            "question": "Why were settlements slow to emerge in Newfoundland?",
            "options": [
                "Due to harsh weather conditions",
                "Because European nations used it as a training ground for navy recruits",
                "Lack of interest from European powers",
                "Constant conflict with indigenous peoples"
            ],
            "answer": "Because European nations used it as a training ground for navy recruits",
            "id": 56
        },
        {
            "question": "What drew French sailors to Plaisance?",
            "options": [
                "The temperate climate",
                "The rocky beaches suitable for drying fish",
                "Gold deposits",
                "The natural harbor for defense"
            ],
            "answer": "The rocky beaches suitable for drying fish",
            "id": 57
        },
        {
            "question": "Who established the French settlement at Tadoussac?",
            "options": [
                "Fran\u00e7ois Grav\u00e9 du Pont and Pierre de Chauvin de Tonnetuit",
                "Samuel de Champlain and Jacques Cartier",
                "Louis XIII and Cardinal Richelieu",
                "Henry IV and Marquis de la Roche"
            ],
            "answer": "Fran\u00e7ois Grav\u00e9 du Pont and Pierre de Chauvin de Tonnetuit",
            "id": 58
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the 'H' in the Montreal Canadiens' crest stand for?",
            "options": [
                "Habitants",
                "Hockey",
                "H\u00e9ritage",
                "Honour"
            ],
            "answer": "Habitants",
            "id": 59
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Champlain establish the settlement of Quebec?",
            "options": [
                "1600",
                "1603",
                "1609",
                "1615"
            ],
            "answer": "1609",
            "id": 60
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Champlain do to sustain the French presence in Quebec?",
            "options": [
                "He built a fortified settlement and established alliances with local tribes",
                "He discovered a gold mine",
                "He converted to the local religion",
                "He started a large scale fishing operation"
            ],
            "answer": "He built a fortified settlement and established alliances with local tribes",
            "id": 61
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Native American leader did Champlain meet at Tadoussac?",
            "options": [
                "Begourat",
                "Iroquet",
                "Outchetaguin",
                "Tadodaho"
            ],
            "answer": "Begourat",
            "id": 62
        },
        {
            "question": "Who did the French establish an alliance with against the Haudenosaunee?",
            "options": [
                "The Om\u00e0miwinini and the Wendat",
                "The Innu and the Montagnais",
                "The Algonquin and the Huron",
                "All of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "All of the above",
            "id": 63
        },
        {
            "question": "Why did the French ally with native tribes?",
            "options": [
                "For military protection",
                "To learn agricultural techniques",
                "To engage in the fur trade",
                "To spread Christianity"
            ],
            "answer": "To engage in the fur trade",
            "id": 64
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the impact of Champlain's death in 1635?",
            "options": [
                "The end of the fur trade",
                "The collapse of French alliances with native tribes",
                "The withdrawal of the French from North America",
                "None of the above"
            ],
            "answer": "None of the above",
            "id": 65
        },
        {
            "question": "Who did La Tour seek support from when his fortunes were slipping?",
            "options": [
                "The Wabanaki",
                "His family",
                "Fellow Protestant network in the New England port",
                "French Catholic missionaries"
            ],
            "answer": "Fellow Protestant network in the New England port",
            "id": 66
        },
        {
            "question": "What did official French Catholicism in the colonies permit?",
            "options": [
                "It permitted only Catholic governors",
                "It did not permit any Protestant governors",
                "It permitted a Protestant governor",
                "It permitted resident priests only"
            ],
            "answer": "It permitted a Protestant governor",
            "id": 67
        },
        {
            "question": "What was d\u2019Aulnay\u2019s highest achievement as governor?",
            "options": [
                "Building Fortress of Louisbourg",
                "The draining of the salt marshes",
                "Leading Wabanaki troops",
                "Marrying La Tour\u2019s widow"
            ],
            "answer": "The draining of the salt marshes",
            "id": 68
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following best describes Acadia's economy?",
            "options": [
                "Isolated and traditional",
                "Integrative and imaginative",
                "Dependent on France",
                "Solely based on fishery"
            ],
            "answer": "Integrative and imaginative",
            "id": 69
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the result of the conflict between d\u2019Aulnay and La Tour?",
            "options": [
                "Continuation of the civil war",
                "La Tour was executed",
                "d\u2019Aulnay exiled La Tour",
                "Reconciliation through marriage"
            ],
            "answer": "Reconciliation through marriage",
            "id": 70
        },
        {
            "question": "What geographic challenges did Acadia face?",
            "options": [
                "Desertification of lands",
                "Landlocked with no access to sea",
                "Vulnerability due to land and sea frontiers",
                "Overpopulation and urban sprawl"
            ],
            "answer": "Vulnerability due to land and sea frontiers",
            "id": 71
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was Fort Castine located?",
            "options": [
                "On the Penobscot River in central Maine",
                "At the mouth of the Saint John River",
                "Near the Bay of Fundy",
                "On \u00cele Royale"
            ],
            "answer": "On the Penobscot River in central Maine",
            "id": 72
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the Treaty of Utrecht (1713) result in for the French?",
            "options": [
                "They gained control over Newfoundland",
                "They began the fortification of Placentia",
                "They lost their position in Newfoundland",
                "They established the Fortress of Louisbourg"
            ],
            "answer": "They lost their position in Newfoundland",
            "id": 73
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the French use Tadoussac primarily for?",
            "options": [
                "A military outpost",
                "Hunting seals and whales",
                "Agricultural development",
                "Trading post for furs"
            ],
            "answer": "Hunting seals and whales",
            "id": 74
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were Fran\u00e7ois Grav\u00e9 du Pont and Pierre de Chauvin de Tonnetuit?",
            "options": [
                "Governors of New France",
                "English explorers",
                "Leaders in establishing the first fur-trade monopoly",
                "French military commanders"
            ],
            "answer": "Leaders in establishing the first fur-trade monopoly",
            "id": 75
        },
        {
            "question": "What conflict did Champlain become involved in during his 1609 visit?",
            "options": [
                "The Seven Years' War",
                "The conflict with the Mohawk",
                "The French and Indian War",
                "The War of the Spanish Succession"
            ],
            "answer": "The conflict with the Mohawk",
            "id": 76
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the 'H' in the Montreal Canadiens' logo stand for?",
            "options": [
                "Hockey",
                "Habitants",
                "Heritage",
                "Honor"
            ],
            "answer": "Habitants",
            "id": 77
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were referred to as 'Canadiens' before the Conquest?",
            "options": [
                "People in the colony of Canada with English ancestry",
                "People in the colony of Canada with French ancestry",
                "Indigenous people of the St. Lawrence Valley",
                "British colonists in New France"
            ],
            "answer": "People in the colony of Canada with French ancestry",
            "id": 78
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did Champlain begin establishing a forward post at Quebec?",
            "options": [
                "1600",
                "1609",
                "1615",
                "1627"
            ],
            "answer": "1609",
            "id": 79
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European monarch granted the first fur-trade monopoly?",
            "options": [
                "King Henry IV of France",
                "King Louis XIII of France",
                "Queen Elizabeth I of England",
                "King Philip II of Spain"
            ],
            "answer": "King Henry IV of France",
            "id": 80
        },
        {
            "question": "Why did the French crown take a greater role in the administration of New France after 1627?",
            "options": [
                "Because of the fur trade monopoly's failure",
                "Due to Champlain's request",
                "Following a war with the English",
                "After the Treaty of Utrecht"
            ],
            "answer": "Because of the fur trade monopoly's failure",
            "id": 81
        },
        {
            "question": "What aspect of the land made agriculture in New France difficult?",
            "options": [
                "The climate was too cold for crops",
                "There were too many forests to clear",
                "The soil was too rocky and infertile",
                "There was a lack of farming technology"
            ],
            "answer": "The soil was too rocky and infertile",
            "id": 82
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the focus of the early economy in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Manufacturing",
                "Agriculture",
                "Fur trade",
                "Gold mining"
            ],
            "answer": "Fur trade",
            "id": 83
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the Compagnie des Cent-Associ\u00e9s?",
            "options": [
                "A military alliance",
                "A religious order",
                "An agricultural collective",
                "A trading company"
            ],
            "answer": "A trading company",
            "id": 84
        },
        {
            "question": "Who established the first French settlement at Port Royal?",
            "options": [
                "Pierre Dugua, Sieur de Mons",
                "Jacques Cartier",
                "Samuel de Champlain",
                "Fran\u00e7ois Grav\u00e9 du Pont"
            ],
            "answer": "Pierre Dugua, Sieur de Mons",
            "id": 85
        },
        {
            "question": "What made New France different from Spanish and English colonies?",
            "options": [
                "It had no permanent settlements",
                "It was solely a military outpost",
                "It had a strong fur trade and was less focused on agriculture",
                "It had no contact with indigenous peoples"
            ],
            "answer": "It had a strong fur trade and was less focused on agriculture",
            "id": 86
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary reason for the slow population growth in New France?",
            "options": [
                "High mortality rates due to disease",
                "Lack of interest from the French",
                "Continuous warfare with indigenous peoples",
                "Harsh climate and living conditions"
            ],
            "answer": "Lack of interest from the French",
            "id": 87
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Jean Talon do to encourage population growth?",
            "options": [
                "Introduced cash incentives for large families",
                "Mandated the construction of schools",
                "Banned the fur trade to encourage farming",
                "Forced military personnel to settle and farm"
            ],
            "answer": "Introduced cash incentives for large families",
            "id": 88
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the Great Peace of Montreal?",
            "options": [
                "A treaty with the British",
                "A declaration of French sovereignty",
                "An end to hostilities between the French and several indigenous groups",
                "The establishment of a fur trade monopoly"
            ],
            "answer": "An end to hostilities between the French and several indigenous groups",
            "id": 89
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary role of women in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Diplomatic relations",
                "Education and literacy",
                "Agricultural labor",
                "Managing households and raising children"
            ],
            "answer": "Managing households and raising children",
            "id": 90
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary cause of the slow population growth in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Harsh winters",
                "Diseases like scurvy",
                "Lack of interest from the French",
                "Warfare with the Haudenosaunee"
            ],
            "answer": "Lack of interest from the French",
            "id": 91
        },
        {
            "question": "What was l'Ordre de Bon Temps?",
            "options": [
                "A military order",
                "An agricultural program",
                "A social and entertainment club",
                "A trade agreement"
            ],
            "answer": "A social and entertainment club",
            "id": 92
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the status of Samuel de Champlain's marriage with H\u00e9l\u00e8ne Boull\u00e9 during its early years?",
            "options": [
                "They were happily married",
                "It was a marriage of convenience for a dowry",
                "They were separated",
                "It was annulled"
            ],
            "answer": "It was a marriage of convenience for a dowry",
            "id": 93
        },
        {
            "question": "What did Samuel de Champlain do when he was faced with harsh winters in Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "Established l'Ordre de Bon Temps",
                "Left Acadia for France",
                "Negotiated with local Indigenous peoples",
                "Focused on mapping and exploration"
            ],
            "answer": "Established l'Ordre de Bon Temps",
            "id": 94
        },
        {
            "question": "What year did Samuel de Champlain die?",
            "options": [
                "1625",
                "1635",
                "1645",
                "1655"
            ],
            "answer": "1635",
            "id": 95
        },
        {
            "question": "Who did Champlain adopt as his daughters?",
            "options": [
                "Children from France",
                "Daughters of the French nobility",
                "Daughters from the Algonquin nation",
                "Children of the Haudenosaunee"
            ],
            "answer": "Daughters from the Algonquin nation",
            "id": 96
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a major consequence of Wendake's collapse for New France?",
            "options": [
                "It initiated a period of peace",
                "It disrupted the trade network",
                "It increased French dependence on Indigenous nations",
                "It improved relations with the Haudenosaunee"
            ],
            "answer": "It disrupted the trade network",
            "id": 97
        },
        {
            "question": "What opportunity did the collapse of Wendake provide for Canada?",
            "options": [
                "Becoming the granary of the north",
                "Forming an alliance with the Haudenosaunee",
                "Expanding into new territories",
                "Creating a monopoly over the fur trade"
            ],
            "answer": "Becoming the granary of the north",
            "id": 98
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main role of coureurs de bois in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Military defense",
                "Agricultural development",
                "Freighting service and trade facilitation",
                "Education and literacy"
            ],
            "answer": "Freighting service and trade facilitation",
            "id": 99
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did New France become a royal colony?",
            "options": [
                "1653",
                "1663",
                "1673",
                "1683"
            ],
            "answer": "1663",
            "id": 100
        },
        {
            "question": "What were the filles du roi sent to New France to do?",
            "options": [
                "Teach",
                "Marry and start families",
                "Trade",
                "Serve in the military"
            ],
            "answer": "Marry and start families",
            "id": 101
        },
        {
            "question": "Who became the king of France in 1643?",
            "options": [
                "Louis XIII",
                "Louis XIV",
                "Louis XV",
                "Louis XVI"
            ],
            "answer": "Louis XIV",
            "id": 102
        },
        {
            "question": "Which regiment was sent to New France to counter the Haudenosaunee threat?",
            "options": [
                "Normandie Regiment",
                "Carignan-Sali\u00e8res Regiment",
                "Picardie Regiment",
                "Navarre Regiment"
            ],
            "answer": "Carignan-Sali\u00e8res Regiment",
            "id": 103
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the chief minister of France before Louis XIV began his personal rule?",
            "options": [
                "Cardinal Richelieu",
                "Cardinal Mazarin",
                "Jean-Baptiste Colbert",
                "Duke of Sully"
            ],
            "answer": "Cardinal Mazarin",
            "id": 104
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the aim of sending the filles du roi to New France?",
            "options": [
                "To establish schools",
                "To increase the military presence",
                "To boost population growth",
                "To start new businesses"
            ],
            "answer": "To boost population growth",
            "id": 105
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the function of engag\u00e9s in New France?",
            "options": [
                "To serve as indentured servants",
                "To act as military officers",
                "To oversee colonial administration",
                "To promote religious conversion"
            ],
            "answer": "To serve as indentured servants",
            "id": 106
        },
        {
            "question": "What role did Jean Talon play in the development of New France?",
            "options": [
                "He was a military leader",
                "He served as Intendant",
                "He was a missionary",
                "He was an explorer"
            ],
            "answer": "He served as Intendant",
            "id": 107
        },
        {
            "question": "Which treaty returned Quebec to French control after its initial capture by the English?",
            "options": [
                "Treaty of Utrecht",
                "Treaty of Ryswick",
                "Treaty of Saint-Germain-en-Laye",
                "Treaty of Paris"
            ],
            "answer": "Treaty of Saint-Germain-en-Laye",
            "id": 108
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a key factor in the eventual defeat of New France by British forces?",
            "options": [
                "Superior British naval power",
                "Lack of support from the French government",
                "Alliances with more Indigenous nations by the British",
                "Harsh climate conditions"
            ],
            "answer": "Superior British naval power",
            "id": 109
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the long-term impact of the British conquest on the French settlers in Canada?",
            "options": [
                "They were forced to leave",
                "They adapted to British rule and maintained their cultural identity",
                "They lost their language and culture",
                "They were assimilated into the British military"
            ],
            "answer": "They adapted to British rule and maintained their cultural identity",
            "id": 110
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a common misunderstanding by Europeans regarding Indigenous leadership structures?",
            "options": [
                "They understood them as hierarchical systems",
                "They saw them as egalitarian",
                "They recognized the consensus-based approach",
                "They interpreted them as loose affiliations without leadership"
            ],
            "answer": "They understood them as hierarchical systems",
            "id": 111
        },
        {
            "question": "What was one reason the Indigenous peoples were considering whether Europeans were beneficial for them?",
            "options": [
                "Trade opportunities",
                "Technological advancements",
                "Religious conversions",
                "Potential alliances against other tribes"
            ],
            "answer": "Trade opportunities",
            "id": 112
        },
        {
            "question": "Which nation was early to decide the French were unwelcome, making the colonial enterprise more tenuous?",
            "options": [
                "The Five Nations",
                "The Wendat",
                "The Algonquin",
                "The Haudenosaunee"
            ],
            "answer": "The Five Nations",
            "id": 113
        },
        {
            "question": "What period is described as the 'heroic age of New France'?",
            "options": [
                "1600 to 1663",
                "1500 to 1550",
                "1700 to 1750",
                "1650 to 1700"
            ],
            "answer": "1600 to 1663",
            "id": 114
        },
        {
            "question": "Samuel de Champlain is recognized for his talents in what field?",
            "options": [
                "Cartography",
                "Drama",
                "Medicine",
                "Law"
            ],
            "answer": "Cartography",
            "id": 115
        },
        {
            "question": "Which order did Champlain establish to uplift spirits during a harsh winter in Acadia?",
            "options": [
                "L'Ordre de Bon Temps",
                "L'Ordre de Champlain",
                "L'Ordre de Nouvelle-France",
                "L'Ordre de la Couronne"
            ],
            "answer": "L'Ordre de Bon Temps",
            "id": 116
        },
        {
            "question": "What injury did Champlain NOT sustain during his leadership in regional wars?",
            "options": [
                "An arrow in the leg",
                "An arrow in the neck",
                "Two arrows in the knee",
                "A musket ball in the arm"
            ],
            "answer": "A musket ball in the arm",
            "id": 117
        },
        {
            "question": "How was Champlain's claim that Hudson Bay was not the Pacific Ocean later validated?",
            "options": [
                "Spanish exploration",
                "British proof",
                "French naval expeditions",
                "Indigenous testimony"
            ],
            "answer": "British proof",
            "id": 118
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the age of Champlain's wife, H\u00e9l\u00e8ne Boull\u00e9, when he married her?",
            "options": [
                "12 years old",
                "14 years old",
                "16 years old",
                "18 years old"
            ],
            "answer": "12 years old",
            "id": 119
        },
        {
            "question": "What nationality were the three daughters that Champlain adopted?",
            "options": [
                "French",
                "Spanish",
                "Algonquin",
                "Haudenosaunee"
            ],
            "answer": "Algonquin",
            "id": 120
        },
        {
            "question": "Which significant event happened between the years 1649 and 1663 that affected Canada?",
            "options": [
                "The establishment of Quebec",
                "The dispersal of Wendake (Huronia)",
                "The founding of Montreal",
                "The signing of a major treaty with Indigenous peoples"
            ],
            "answer": "The dispersal of Wendake (Huronia)",
            "id": 121
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the impact of the Wendake collapse on French colonial trade?",
            "options": [
                "It strengthened it",
                "It created a monopoly",
                "It caused a trade surplus",
                "It weakened the trade network"
            ],
            "answer": "It weakened the trade network",
            "id": 122
        },
        {
            "question": "Who became king of France in 1643?",
            "options": [
                "Louis XIII",
                "Louis XIV",
                "Henry IV",
                "Charles IX"
            ],
            "answer": "Louis XIV",
            "id": 123
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the role of the Carignan-Sali\u00e8res Regiment in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Establishing schools",
                "Building infrastructure",
                "Countering the Haudenosaunee threat",
                "Exploring the West"
            ],
            "answer": "Countering the Haudenosaunee threat",
            "id": 124
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the purpose of sending the 'filles du roi' to New France?",
            "options": [
                "To educate the population",
                "To marry them off and boost population growth",
                "To help in trade",
                "To convert the Indigenous peoples"
            ],
            "answer": "To marry them off and boost population growth",
            "id": 125
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did New France become a royal colony?",
            "options": [
                "1600",
                "1663",
                "1701",
                "1763"
            ],
            "answer": "1663",
            "id": 126
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the 'Code Noir' primarily concerning?",
            "options": [
                "Trade regulations",
                "Behavior of soldiers",
                "Treatment of slaves",
                "Marriage laws"
            ],
            "answer": "Treatment of slaves",
            "id": 127
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the intent of the 'Code Noir'?",
            "options": [
                "To abolish slavery",
                "To regulate the treatment and condition of slaves",
                "To define the legal status of Indigenous peoples",
                "To set trade guidelines"
            ],
            "answer": "To regulate the treatment and condition of slaves",
            "id": 128
        },
        {
            "question": "Who led the Hudson's Bay Company to be formed?",
            "options": [
                "Samuel de Champlain",
                "Prince Rupert",
                "Louis Jolliet",
                "Jacques Cartier"
            ],
            "answer": "Prince Rupert",
            "id": 129
        },
        {
            "question": "What resource was crucial for the profitability of the Hudson's Bay Company?",
            "options": [
                "Timber",
                "Beaver pelts",
                "Gold",
                "Fish"
            ],
            "answer": "Beaver pelts",
            "id": 130
        },
        {
            "question": "Which group was not part of the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham'?",
            "options": [
                "French",
                "British",
                "Haudenosaunee",
                "Algonquin"
            ],
            "answer": "Algonquin",
            "id": 131
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the treaty that concluded the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham'?",
            "options": [
                "Treaty of Paris",
                "Treaty of Utrecht",
                "Treaty of Versailles",
                "Treaty of Westminster"
            ],
            "answer": "Treaty of Paris",
            "id": 132
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year did the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham' take place?",
            "options": [
                "1759",
                "1763",
                "1776",
                "1783"
            ],
            "answer": "1759",
            "id": 133
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the French commander at the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham'?",
            "options": [
                "Marquis de Montcalm",
                "Samuel de Champlain",
                "Jean Talon",
                "Louis de Buade"
            ],
            "answer": "Marquis de Montcalm",
            "id": 134
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a significant result of the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham' for New France?",
            "options": [
                "It became a British colony",
                "It expanded its territory",
                "It established a new government",
                "It began trading with Spain"
            ],
            "answer": "It became a British colony",
            "id": 135
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the British commander at the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham'?",
            "options": [
                "General James Wolfe",
                "Admiral Horatio Nelson",
                "Sir Francis Drake",
                "General Edward Braddock"
            ],
            "answer": "General James Wolfe",
            "id": 136
        },
        {
            "question": "Which European power gained control of New France following the 'Battle of the Plains of Abraham'?",
            "options": [
                "Britain",
                "Spain",
                "Portugal",
                "The Netherlands"
            ],
            "answer": "Britain",
            "id": 137
        },
        {
            "question": "What was one long-term effect of the British conquest of New France?",
            "options": [
                "The strengthening of French language and culture",
                "The assimilation of French settlers into British culture",
                "The unification of Indigenous and European societies",
                "The foundation of bilingualism in Canadian governance"
            ],
            "answer": "The foundation of bilingualism in Canadian governance",
            "id": 138
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Indigenous group was an important ally to the British during the conquest of New France?",
            "options": [
                "The Algonquin",
                "The Cree",
                "The Haudenosaunee",
                "The Mi'kmaq"
            ],
            "answer": "The Haudenosaunee",
            "id": 139
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was appointed as the first intendant of the colonies in the 17th century?",
            "options": [
                "Jean Talon",
                "Louis XIV",
                "Jean-Baptiste Colbert",
                "Ren\u00e9-Robert Cavalier de La Salle"
            ],
            "answer": "Jean Talon",
            "id": 140
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the role of the Sulpicians in Montreal during the 17th century?",
            "options": [
                "They were a military regiment",
                "They were a group of habitants",
                "They owned engag\u00e9 contracts",
                "They were shipbuilders"
            ],
            "answer": "They owned engag\u00e9 contracts",
            "id": 141
        },
        {
            "question": "Which religious order was Jeanne Mance a member of?",
            "options": [
                "The Ursuline order of nuns",
                "The Society of Jesus",
                "The Sulpicians",
                "The Society of Notre-Dame"
            ],
            "answer": "The Ursuline order of nuns",
            "id": 142
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary work of engag\u00e9s in the colony?",
            "options": [
                "Trade negotiations",
                "Farming",
                "Military service",
                "Religious duties"
            ],
            "answer": "Farming",
            "id": 143
        },
        {
            "question": "Between which years was Jean Talon appointed for his two terms as the intendant?",
            "options": [
                "1663\u20131672 and 1670\u20131682",
                "1663\u20131668 and 1670\u20131672",
                "1665\u20131670 and 1672\u20131674",
                "1660\u20131665 and 1668\u20131673"
            ],
            "answer": "1663\u20131668 and 1670\u20131672",
            "id": 144
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of economic system was Jean-Baptiste Colbert planning to introduce in the colonies?",
            "options": [
                "Socialism",
                "Mercantilism",
                "Capitalism",
                "Feudalism"
            ],
            "answer": "Mercantilism",
            "id": 145
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name given to the women sent by the king to increase the population of the colony?",
            "options": [
                "Les Dames de la Cour",
                "Les Filles de la Charit\u00e9",
                "Les Filles du Roi",
                "Les Femmes de la Colonie"
            ],
            "answer": "Les Filles du Roi",
            "id": 146
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a major role of the clergy according to Colbert's plans for the colony?",
            "options": [
                "Military defense",
                "Economic development",
                "Defer to the king over Rome",
                "Manage fur trade"
            ],
            "answer": "Defer to the king over Rome",
            "id": 147
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the economic focus of Jean Talon's strategy for the colony?",
            "options": [
                "Building up agricultural output",
                "Increasing military presence",
                "Promoting religious missions",
                "Expanding urban areas"
            ],
            "answer": "Building up agricultural output",
            "id": 148
        },
        {
            "question": "What system of landholding was introduced in the colony to resemble French feudalism?",
            "options": [
                "Capitalist system",
                "Seigneurial system",
                "Communist system",
                "Republican system"
            ],
            "answer": "Seigneurial system",
            "id": 149
        },
        {
            "question": "What title did Louis de Buade hold?",
            "options": [
                "Governor",
                "Intendant",
                "Seigneur",
                "Ministre de la Marine"
            ],
            "answer": "Governor",
            "id": 150
        },
        {
            "question": "Which disease outbreak in 1687 claimed 6% of the colonist population of Montreal?",
            "options": [
                "Bubonic Plague",
                "Measles",
                "Cholera",
                "Smallpox"
            ],
            "answer": "Measles",
            "id": 151
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main reason for the lack of settlement in seigneuries before the 1730s?",
            "options": [
                "Lack of interest from the seigneurs",
                "Attacks by the Haudenosaunee",
                "Poor soil fertility",
                "Harsh climatic conditions"
            ],
            "answer": "Attacks by the Haudenosaunee",
            "id": 152
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of colony was Frontenac pursuing that contradicted the goals of Paris?",
            "options": [
                "Compact colony",
                "Expansive colony",
                "Industrial colony",
                "Military colony"
            ],
            "answer": "Expansive colony",
            "id": 153
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the seigneurs owe the king as part of their duty?",
            "options": [
                "An annual tribute",
                "A military service",
                "An oath of loyalty",
                "A portion of their crops"
            ],
            "answer": "An oath of loyalty",
            "id": 154
        },
        {
            "question": "What were habitants?",
            "options": [
                "Local administrators",
                "Fur traders",
                "Soldiers",
                "Farmers"
            ],
            "answer": "Farmers",
            "id": 155
        },
        {
            "question": "Who held absolute power in New France?",
            "options": [
                "The intendant",
                "The king",
                "The governor",
                "The bishop"
            ],
            "answer": "The king",
            "id": 156
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main role of the bishop in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Military leadership",
                "Judicial power",
                "Spiritual and educational leadership",
                "Economic planning"
            ],
            "answer": "Spiritual and educational leadership",
            "id": 157
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the group of Iroquoian-speaking indigenous people who lived near the St. Lawrence River?",
            "options": [
                "The Haudenosaunee",
                "The Algonquins",
                "The Hurons",
                "The Stadaconans"
            ],
            "answer": "The Stadaconans",
            "id": 158
        },
        {
            "question": "Which French explorer was responsible for claiming Canada for France in 1534?",
            "options": [
                "Jacques Cartier",
                "Samuel de Champlain",
                "Ren\u00e9-Robert Cavalier de La Salle",
                "Pierre Dugua, Sieur de Mons"
            ],
            "answer": "Jacques Cartier",
            "id": 159
        },
        {
            "question": "What impact did the Treaty of Utrecht have on the expansion in Canada?",
            "options": [
                "It halted expansion completely",
                "It had no effect on expansion",
                "It intensified expansionist tendencies in Canada",
                "It only affected the French expansion"
            ],
            "answer": "It intensified expansionist tendencies in Canada",
            "id": 160
        },
        {
            "question": "What areas were handed over to the British after the Treaty of Utrecht?",
            "options": [
                "Hudson Bay, Newfoundland, and Acadia",
                "Quebec and Montreal",
                "Louisbourg and the Great Lakes",
                "Pays d\u2019en Haut and St. Lawrence River"
            ],
            "answer": "Hudson Bay, Newfoundland, and Acadia",
            "id": 161
        },
        {
            "question": "By mid-18th century, what was the average completed family size in Canada?",
            "options": [
                "Between 2 and 4 children",
                "Between 6 and 8 children",
                "Between 10 and 12 children",
                "More than 12 children"
            ],
            "answer": "Between 6 and 8 children",
            "id": 162
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the approximate population of Quebec around 1760?",
            "options": [
                "5000",
                "8000",
                "10,000",
                "15,000"
            ],
            "answer": "8000",
            "id": 163
        },
        {
            "question": "What did wealthy and influential merchants in the colony of New France struggle to achieve?",
            "options": [
                "Independence from France",
                "Control over the fur trade",
                "The status of a seigneur",
                "Expansion into British territories"
            ],
            "answer": "The status of a seigneur",
            "id": 164
        },
        {
            "question": "Which monastic order first arrived in New France in 1615 to Christianize the locals?",
            "options": [
                "The Franciscans",
                "The Dominicans",
                "The Recollets",
                "The Benedictines"
            ],
            "answer": "The Recollets",
            "id": 165
        },
        {
            "question": "Who replaced the Recollets when they were evicted from the colony in 1629?",
            "options": [
                "The Jesuits",
                "The Anglicans",
                "The Methodists",
                "The Lutherans"
            ],
            "answer": "The Jesuits",
            "id": 166
        },
        {
            "question": "During which war did prices of fur continue to fall?",
            "options": [
                "The Seven Years' War",
                "The War of the Spanish Succession",
                "The French and Indian War",
                "The American Revolutionary War"
            ],
            "answer": "The War of the Spanish Succession",
            "id": 167
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary reason for more furs being supplied when prices were low?",
            "options": [
                "Increased demand in Europe",
                "Indigenous suppliers needed to trade more for their wants",
                "Overhunting of fur-bearing animals",
                "French imposed quotas"
            ],
            "answer": "Indigenous suppliers needed to trade more for their wants",
            "id": 168
        },
        {
            "question": "What relationship did Canadien merchants have with the merchants in France?",
            "options": [
                "Competitive",
                "Dependent",
                "Hostile",
                "Unrelated"
            ],
            "answer": "Dependent",
            "id": 169
        },
        {
            "question": "Which city had a population of about 3500 around 1760?",
            "options": [
                "Quebec",
                "Montreal",
                "Louisbourg",
                "Acadia"
            ],
            "answer": "Montreal",
            "id": 170
        },
        {
            "question": "What were Canadiens and Canadiennes known to inappropriately appropriate in the new country?",
            "options": [
                "Land",
                "Titles such as \u00e9\u200bcuyer",
                "Goods from fur trade",
                "British identities"
            ],
            "answer": "Titles such as \u00e9\u200bcuyer",
            "id": 171
        },
        {
            "question": "What force was considered more powerful than the police force in regulating domestic relations in Canadien society?",
            "options": [
                "Military authority",
                "Clerical supervision",
                "Gossip",
                "Judicial intervention"
            ],
            "answer": "Gossip",
            "id": 172
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the Treaty of Utrecht (1713) conclude in North America?",
            "options": [
                "The War of the Spanish Succession",
                "The Great Peace of 1701",
                "The French and Indian War",
                "The Seven Years' War"
            ],
            "answer": "The War of the Spanish Succession",
            "id": 173
        },
        {
            "question": "How was the population growth in New France primarily achieved?",
            "options": [
                "Wave-after-wave of immigration",
                "Natural increase",
                "Import of slaves",
                "Relocation of French citizens"
            ],
            "answer": "Natural increase",
            "id": 174
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main objective of the French regime's agenda in its early years of colonial activity?",
            "options": [
                "Establishing a fur trade monopoly",
                "Christianizing the Indigenous peoples",
                "Expanding territorial claims",
                "Creating a self-sustaining colony"
            ],
            "answer": "Christianizing the Indigenous peoples",
            "id": 175
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two religious orders had different approaches to Christianizing Indigenous peoples in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Recollets and Jesuits",
                "Dominicans and Franciscans",
                "Benedictines and Carmelites",
                "Augustinians and Capuchins"
            ],
            "answer": "Recollets and Jesuits",
            "id": 176
        },
        {
            "question": "When was Quebec City viewed as depicted in the media attribution?",
            "options": [
                "1600",
                "1650",
                "1700",
                "1750"
            ],
            "answer": "1700",
            "id": 177
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the cause of the Wendat Confederacy's collapse in 1649?",
            "options": [
                "Natural disasters",
                "Defeats by smallpox and the Haudenosaunee",
                "Economic collapse",
                "French military conquest"
            ],
            "answer": "Defeats by smallpox and the Haudenosaunee",
            "id": 178
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the first French traders to reach the western shore of Lake Superior in 1659?",
            "options": [
                "Jacques Cartier and Samuel de Champlain",
                "Louis Jolliet and Jacques Marquette",
                "Pierre-Esprit Radisson and M\u00e9dard Chouart des Groseilliers",
                "Fran\u00e7ois de La V\u00e9rendrye and his sons"
            ],
            "answer": "Pierre-Esprit Radisson and M\u00e9dard Chouart des Groseilliers",
            "id": 179
        },
        {
            "question": "Which year marks the founding of Louisiana in the Mississippi basin?",
            "options": [
                "1659",
                "1670",
                "1699",
                "1713"
            ],
            "answer": "1699",
            "id": 180
        },
        {
            "question": "Who founded the first permanent settlement in Louisiana, Fort Maurepas?",
            "options": [
                "Robert de La Salle",
                "Louis Jolliet",
                "Pierre Le Moyne d\u2019Iberville",
                "Antoine de la Mothe Cadillac"
            ],
            "answer": "Pierre Le Moyne d\u2019Iberville",
            "id": 181
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main economic activity in early Louisiana?",
            "options": [
                "Sugar plantations",
                "Fur trading",
                "Cotton plantations",
                "Gold mining"
            ],
            "answer": "Cotton plantations",
            "id": 182
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary function of the extensive system of fortifications in New France?",
            "options": [
                "Defense against Indigenous uprisings",
                "Protection from wild animals",
                "Maintaining a trading network",
                "As tourist attractions"
            ],
            "answer": "Maintaining a trading network",
            "id": 183
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the strategic value of Louisiana and the Ohio in New France?",
            "options": [
                "They were cultural centers",
                "They contained large populations",
                "They helped contain British expansion",
                "They were rich in gold"
            ],
            "answer": "They helped contain British expansion",
            "id": 184
        },
        {
            "question": "During which conflict were the French able to exploit Indigenous dissatisfaction with British colonists?",
            "options": [
                "King William's War",
                "Queen Anne's War",
                "The Beaver Wars",
                "The War of Spanish Succession"
            ],
            "answer": "Queen Anne's War",
            "id": 185
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the diplomatic strategy the French used to maintain good relations with Indigenous communities?",
            "options": [
                "Military alliances",
                "Religious conversions",
                "Gift diplomacy",
                "Technological exchange"
            ],
            "answer": "Gift diplomacy",
            "id": 186
        },
        {
            "question": "Which two valleys served as bridges between Louisiana and Canada?",
            "options": [
                "The Red River and Rio Grande Valleys",
                "The Ohio and Illinois Valleys",
                "The Shenandoah and Hudson Valleys",
                "The Missouri and Platte Valleys"
            ],
            "answer": "The Ohio and Illinois Valleys",
            "id": 187
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a consequence of the Beaver Wars in terms of territory?",
            "options": [
                "The French lost control of the St. Lawrence River",
                "The Haudenosaunee expanded westward",
                "The British gained access to the Great Lakes",
                "Louisiana expanded to the east"
            ],
            "answer": "The Haudenosaunee expanded westward",
            "id": 188
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary economic exchange product in Louisiana similar to the beaver pelts in Canada?",
            "options": [
                "Cotton",
                "Tobacco",
                "Deer skins",
                "Alligator hides"
            ],
            "answer": "Deer skins",
            "id": 189
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the first French traders to reach the western shore of Lake Superior?",
            "options": [
                "Jacques Cartier and Samuel de Champlain",
                "Louis Jolliet and Jacques Marquette",
                "Pierre-Esprit Radisson and M\u00e9dard Chouart des Groseilliers",
                "Ren\u00e9-Robert Cavelier, Sieur de La Salle and Henri de Tonti"
            ],
            "answer": "Pierre-Esprit Radisson and M\u00e9dard Chouart des Groseilliers",
            "id": 190
        },
        {
            "question": "In what year was Louisiana founded in the basin of the Mississippi?",
            "options": [
                "1679",
                "1699",
                "1713",
                "1720"
            ],
            "answer": "1699",
            "id": 191
        },
        {
            "question": "Which military officer from Canada founded the first permanent settlement in Louisiana?",
            "options": [
                "Jacques Cartier",
                "Samuel de Champlain",
                "Pierre Le Moyne d'Iberville",
                "Jean-Baptiste Le Moyne de Bienville"
            ],
            "answer": "Pierre Le Moyne d'Iberville",
            "id": 192
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary export of Louisiana for many years?",
            "options": [
                "Beaver pelts",
                "Moose hides",
                "Deer skins",
                "Cotton"
            ],
            "answer": "Deer skins",
            "id": 193
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the French regime introduce during its first decade of colonial activity in New France?",
            "options": [
                "A Christianizing agenda",
                "The seigneurial system",
                "The fur trade",
                "Military fortifications"
            ],
            "answer": "A Christianizing agenda",
            "id": 194
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Indigenous confederacy collapsed in 1649?",
            "options": [
                "The Algonquin Confederacy",
                "The Wendat Confederacy",
                "The Iroquois Confederacy",
                "The Haudenosaunee Confederacy"
            ],
            "answer": "The Wendat Confederacy",
            "id": 195
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the main supplier nation of deer skins to Louisiana?",
            "options": [
                "The Iroquois",
                "The Haudenosaunee",
                "The Wendat",
                "The Choctaw"
            ],
            "answer": "The Choctaw",
            "id": 196
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the French hope to guarantee with gift diplomacy in the Ohio region?",
            "options": [
                "Indigenous support",
                "British trade",
                "Spanish alliance",
                "English colonists' cooperation"
            ],
            "answer": "Indigenous support",
            "id": 197
        },
        {
            "question": "Which code was introduced by Colbert in 1685 to regulate slavery in French colonies?",
            "options": [
                "The Napoleonic Code",
                "The Civil Code",
                "The Code Civil",
                "The Code Noir"
            ],
            "answer": "The Code Noir",
            "id": 198
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was Louisiana's administration principally located?",
            "options": [
                "Quebec City",
                "New Orleans",
                "Mobile",
                "Montreal"
            ],
            "answer": "New Orleans",
            "id": 199
        },
        {
            "question": "Which valleys served as bridges between Louisiana and Canada?",
            "options": [
                "The Ohio and Illinois Valleys",
                "The Red River and Missouri Valleys",
                "The Shenandoah and Hudson Valleys",
                "The Mississippi and Arkansas Valleys"
            ],
            "answer": "The Ohio and Illinois Valleys",
            "id": 200
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the main allies and trading partners of the Chickasaw?",
            "options": [
                "The French in Louisiana",
                "The British in South Carolina",
                "The Spanish in Mexico",
                "The Dutch in New York"
            ],
            "answer": "The British in South Carolina",
            "id": 201
        },
        {
            "question": "What was one of the outcomes of Indigenous slave exchanges for the French?",
            "options": [
                "Strengthening of alliances with all Indigenous nations",
                "Creation of a unified Indigenous front",
                "Limitations on diplomatic engagements with certain Indigenous nations",
                "An increase in French territorial claims"
            ],
            "answer": "Limitations on diplomatic engagements with certain Indigenous nations",
            "id": 202
        },
        {
            "question": "Which war changed hands of the territory in the Ohio Valley between Indigenous groups?",
            "options": [
                "The French and Indian War",
                "The Beaver Wars",
                "King Philip's War",
                "The Pequot War"
            ],
            "answer": "The Beaver Wars",
            "id": 203
        },
        {
            "question": "Which fort is an example of the investment made by Canadien and Louisianan authorities in fortifications?",
            "options": [
                "Fort Maurepas",
                "Fort de Chartres",
                "Fort Frontenac",
                "Fort Niagara"
            ],
            "answer": "Fort de Chartres",
            "id": 204
        },
        {
            "question": "What was one reason for the French settlers' integration into an Indigenous world in Louisiana and Canada?",
            "options": [
                "To control the fur trade",
                "To promote French culture",
                "To resist British expansion",
                "To convert Indigenous peoples to Christianity"
            ],
            "answer": "To control the fur trade",
            "id": 205
        },
        {
            "question": "What led to the development of a French Creole society?",
            "options": [
                "The interaction of French settlers with Indigenous and African peoples",
                "The imposition of French laws and customs on colonies",
                "The exclusive trade with France",
                "The military alliance with Indigenous nations"
            ],
            "answer": "The interaction of French settlers with Indigenous and African peoples",
            "id": 206
        },
        {
            "question": "Which governor of Louisiana was known for his diplomatic skills?",
            "options": [
                "Antoine Laumet de La Mothe, sieur de Cadillac",
                "Jean-Baptiste Le Moyne de Bienville",
                "Pierre Le Moyne d'Iberville",
                "Louis Billouart, Chevalier de Kerlerec"
            ],
            "answer": "Jean-Baptiste Le Moyne de Bienville",
            "id": 207
        },
        {
            "question": "Which river corridor did the Meskwaki control, connecting Lake Michigan to the upper Mississippi valley?",
            "options": [
                "The Ohio River Corridor",
                "The Illinois River Corridor",
                "The Fox River Corridor",
                "The Meskwaki River Corridor"
            ],
            "answer": "The Illinois River Corridor",
            "id": 208
        },
        {
            "question": "What confederation did the Meskwaki act as intermediaries for in trade?",
            "options": [
                "The Council of Three Fires",
                "The Iroquois Confederacy",
                "The Sioux Confederacy",
                "The Algonquin Confederacy"
            ],
            "answer": "The Council of Three Fires",
            "id": 209
        },
        {
            "question": "Which nation did the Wendat, likely armed by the French, displace from southern Ontario?",
            "options": [
                "The Meskwaki",
                "The Anishinaabe/Ojibwa",
                "The Potawatomi",
                "The Ottawa"
            ],
            "answer": "The Meskwaki",
            "id": 210
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the French want to achieve by opposing the Meskwaki?",
            "options": [
                "Unfettered access to the Sioux and the Plains",
                "Control of the river corridor",
                "Expansion of the fur trade",
                "Conversion of Indigenous peoples to Christianity"
            ],
            "answer": "Unfettered access to the Sioux and the Plains",
            "id": 211
        },
        {
            "question": "In which year did the first major conflict of the Fox Wars occur?",
            "options": [
                "1700",
                "1701",
                "1712",
                "1728"
            ],
            "answer": "1701",
            "id": 212
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the name of the fort where the first major conflict of the Fox Wars took place?",
            "options": [
                "Fort Pontchartrain",
                "Fort Detroit",
                "Fort Green Bay",
                "Fort New France"
            ],
            "answer": "Fort Pontchartrain",
            "id": 213
        },
        {
            "question": "Which governor of New France is noted for punishing the Meskwaki during the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "Governor Frontenac",
                "Governor Beauharnois",
                "Governor Cadillac",
                "Governor Vaudreuil"
            ],
            "answer": "Governor Beauharnois",
            "id": 214
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the outcome for the Meskwaki population after the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "They became the dominant power",
                "They were largely integrated into French society",
                "They were nearly extinguished",
                "They migrated to New France"
            ],
            "answer": "They were nearly extinguished",
            "id": 215
        },
        {
            "question": "What position did the principal Fox chief, Kiala, take in 1733?",
            "options": [
                "He led a counterattack against the French",
                "He begged for mercy from the French",
                "He allied with the British",
                "He became a French ambassador"
            ],
            "answer": "He begged for mercy from the French",
            "id": 216
        },
        {
            "question": "Where was the principal Fox chief, Kiala, sent as a slave?",
            "options": [
                "Martinique",
                "Louisiana",
                "New France",
                "Quebec"
            ],
            "answer": "Martinique",
            "id": 217
        },
        {
            "question": "What policy did Governor Beauharnois implement towards the remaining Foxes?",
            "options": [
                "They should be dispersed among missions",
                "They should be accepted as French citizens",
                "They should be given their own land",
                "They should be killed if not dispersed"
            ],
            "answer": "They should be killed if not dispersed",
            "id": 218
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the Fox Wars campaign reveal about the French-Indigenous relations?",
            "options": [
                "They were unqualifiedly positive",
                "They included instances of conflict and violence",
                "They were solely based on trade",
                "They were based on territorial expansion"
            ],
            "answer": "They included instances of conflict and violence",
            "id": 219
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the attitude of the French towards lands in the Pays d\u2019en Haut?",
            "options": [
                "They were indifferent to land ownership",
                "They demanded large concessions of land",
                "They were not interested in annexing lands",
                "They wanted to establish permanent settlements"
            ],
            "answer": "They were not interested in annexing lands",
            "id": 220
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was NOT a result of the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "The enhancement of French diplomacy",
                "The spread of European goods and commerce",
                "The unification of Indigenous nations",
                "The near extinction of the Meskwaki"
            ],
            "answer": "The unification of Indigenous nations",
            "id": 221
        },
        {
            "question": "What region did the Virginian colonists explore for expansion during the time of the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "The Mississippi Delta",
                "The Ohio Valley",
                "The Appalachian Mountains",
                "The Great Lakes"
            ],
            "answer": "The Ohio Valley",
            "id": 222
        },
        {
            "question": "What advantage did the Meskwaki initially hold in the conflict with the French?",
            "options": [
                "Technological superiority",
                "Greater numbers",
                "Control of strategic trade routes",
                "Stronger military alliances"
            ],
            "answer": "Control of strategic trade routes",
            "id": 223
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the impact of European goods, commerce, and military alliances according to the text?",
            "options": [
                "Localized to Canada and Acadia",
                "Negligible across North America",
                "Far-flung impacts across the middle of North America",
                "Only within European settlements"
            ],
            "answer": "Far-flung impacts across the middle of North America",
            "id": 224
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the campaign against the Meskwaki by Governor Beauharnois signify?",
            "options": [
                "An emphasis on peaceful assimilation",
                "A desire to foster equality",
                "A genocidal intent",
                "A diplomatic misunderstanding"
            ],
            "answer": "A genocidal intent",
            "id": 225
        },
        {
            "question": "What kind of trade became lively after the conflict in 1701 at Fort Pontchartrain?",
            "options": [
                "Fur trade",
                "Gold trade",
                "Meskwaki slave trade",
                "Tobacco trade"
            ],
            "answer": "Meskwaki slave trade",
            "id": 226
        },
        {
            "question": "Which nations comprised the Council of Three Fires?",
            "options": [
                "Potawatomi, Ottawa, Anishinaabe/Ojibwa",
                "Sioux, Meskwaki, Mascouten",
                "Iroquois, Algonquin, Huron",
                "Cree, Blackfoot, Assiniboine"
            ],
            "answer": "Potawatomi, Ottawa, Anishinaabe/Ojibwa",
            "id": 227
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the Meskwaki demand from the French that led to the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "Military support",
                "Conversion to Christianity",
                "Concessions of land",
                "Recognition as trade intermediaries"
            ],
            "answer": "Recognition as trade intermediaries",
            "id": 228
        },
        {
            "question": "How did the French generally behave towards Indigenous nations in the territories mentioned?",
            "options": [
                "As conquerors",
                "As guests",
                "As missionaries",
                "As traders only"
            ],
            "answer": "As guests",
            "id": 229
        },
        {
            "question": "What strategy did the French use to maintain alliances with Indigenous nations?",
            "options": [
                "Regular military exercises",
                "Systematic colonization",
                "Regular and systematic gift-giving",
                "Exclusive trade agreements"
            ],
            "answer": "Regular and systematic gift-giving",
            "id": 230
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the duration of the more or less continuous war that picked up again in 1712?",
            "options": [
                "5 years",
                "10 years",
                "15 years",
                "More than 15 years"
            ],
            "answer": "More than 15 years",
            "id": 231
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the fate of the smallest numbers of Meskwaki refugees?",
            "options": [
                "They were given asylum",
                "They were hunted down and executed",
                "They were absorbed into other tribes",
                "They were relocated to French territories"
            ],
            "answer": "They were hunted down and executed",
            "id": 232
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the primary goal of French diplomacy during the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "To establish trade monopolies",
                "To demonstrate military might",
                "To pass the test of strength among allies",
                "To convert Indigenous peoples to Christianity"
            ],
            "answer": "To pass the test of strength among allies",
            "id": 233
        },
        {
            "question": "Which group played a crucial role in the execution of Beauharnois' grim campaign?",
            "options": [
                "French settlers",
                "British traders",
                "Indigenous allies",
                "European diplomats"
            ],
            "answer": "Indigenous allies",
            "id": 234
        },
        {
            "question": "How were the Virginian colonists' position compared to the French during the Fox Wars period?",
            "options": [
                "Stronger than the French",
                "Equivalent to the French",
                "Weaker than the French",
                "Not involved in the regional conflicts"
            ],
            "answer": "Weaker than the French",
            "id": 235
        },
        {
            "question": "What turned the tide against the Meskwaki early in the conflict?",
            "options": [
                "The Meskwaki's strategic errors",
                "French military technology",
                "The Meskwaki's depletion of resources",
                "The intervention of British forces"
            ],
            "answer": "French military technology",
            "id": 236
        },
        {
            "question": "What misconception about French and Indigenous relations does the text aim to correct?",
            "options": [
                "That they were always peaceful",
                "That they were solely economic",
                "That they were culturally driven",
                "That they were always hostile"
            ],
            "answer": "That they were always peaceful",
            "id": 237
        },
        {
            "question": "What river corridor did the Meskwaki control, connecting Lake Michigan to the upper Mississippi valley?",
            "options": [
                "The Fox River",
                "The Wisconsin River",
                "The Illinois River",
                "The Mississippi River"
            ],
            "answer": "The Fox River",
            "id": 238
        },
        {
            "question": "Who were the members of the Council of Three Fires?",
            "options": [
                "The Potawatomi, Ottawa, and Anishinaabe/Ojibwa",
                "The Sioux, Meskwaki, and Potawatomi",
                "The Ottawa, Meskwaki, and Anishinaabe/Ojibwa",
                "The Potawatomi, Sioux, and Ottawa"
            ],
            "answer": "The Potawatomi, Ottawa, and Anishinaabe/Ojibwa",
            "id": 239
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Indigenous group is referred to as the Fox in historical texts?",
            "options": [
                "The Meskwaki",
                "The Potawatomi",
                "The Sioux",
                "The Anishinaabe/Ojibwa"
            ],
            "answer": "The Meskwaki",
            "id": 240
        },
        {
            "question": "What year marked the beginning of the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "1700",
                "1701",
                "1712",
                "1728"
            ],
            "answer": "1701",
            "id": 241
        },
        {
            "question": "Where did the first major conflict of the Fox Wars take place?",
            "options": [
                "Fort Pontchartrain (Detroit)",
                "Green Bay",
                "Fort de Chartres",
                "Martinique"
            ],
            "answer": "Fort Pontchartrain (Detroit)",
            "id": 242
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the Meskwaki become the target of after the first conflict in the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "Trade embargoes",
                "A campaign of integration",
                "A lively traffic in Meskwaki slaves",
                "Diplomatic sanctions"
            ],
            "answer": "A lively traffic in Meskwaki slaves",
            "id": 243
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the governor of New France during the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "Kiala",
                "Beauharnois",
                "Cadillac",
                "Bienville"
            ],
            "answer": "Beauharnois",
            "id": 244
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the fate of the principal Fox chief, Kiala, after the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "He was executed",
                "He was sent to Martinique in slavery",
                "He became an ally to the French",
                "He led his people to safety"
            ],
            "answer": "He was sent to Martinique in slavery",
            "id": 245
        },
        {
            "question": "What was Beauharnois's order regarding the remaining Foxes if they did not disperse?",
            "options": [
                "They were to be integrated into French society",
                "They were to be converted to Christianity",
                "They were to be killed",
                "They were to be relocated to another territory"
            ],
            "answer": "They were to be killed",
            "id": 246
        },
        {
            "question": "Approximately how many Meskwaki survived the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "A few dozen",
                "A few hundred",
                "A few thousand",
                "Their numbers increased"
            ],
            "answer": "A few hundred",
            "id": 247
        },
        {
            "question": "What was one factor that contributed to the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "French demand for land",
                "Meskwaki control of a vital trade route",
                "Meskwaki aggression towards French settlements",
                "French political instability"
            ],
            "answer": "Meskwaki control of a vital trade route",
            "id": 248
        },
        {
            "question": "The French relationship with Indigenous nations was generally positive for several reasons except one. Which one is it?",
            "options": [
                "They did not demand land concessions",
                "They behaved as invaders rather than guests",
                "They maintained alliances through gift diplomacy",
                "They engaged in lucrative trade"
            ],
            "answer": "They behaved as invaders rather than guests",
            "id": 249
        },
        {
            "question": "What was one result of the Fox Wars for the French in terms of alliances?",
            "options": [
                "It weakened their alliances",
                "It had no impact on their alliances",
                "It tested and proved the strength of their alliances",
                "It created new alliances with the British"
            ],
            "answer": "It tested and proved the strength of their alliances",
            "id": 250
        },
        {
            "question": "What did the Fox Wars reveal about the French and Indigenous relations?",
            "options": [
                "They were always harmonious",
                "They were fraught with mutual distrust",
                "They were sometimes contentious and violent",
                "They were based solely on economic interests"
            ],
            "answer": "They were sometimes contentious and violent",
            "id": 251
        },
        {
            "question": "What impact did European goods, commerce, and military alliances have in North America?",
            "options": [
                "Limited to Canada",
                "Limited to Acadia",
                "Limited to the Mississippi Delta",
                "Far-flung impacts across the middle of North America"
            ],
            "answer": "Far-flung impacts across the middle of North America",
            "id": 252
        },
        {
            "question": "What stance did the French take towards land annexation in North America?",
            "options": [
                "They actively sought to annex lands",
                "They were indifferent to land ownership",
                "They were not interested in annexing lands",
                "They wanted to convert all lands to agricultural use"
            ],
            "answer": "They were not interested in annexing lands",
            "id": 253
        },
        {
            "question": "What was a driving factor behind the actions of the French in North America, according to the text?",
            "options": [
                "Greed and pride",
                "Religious fervor",
                "Desire for peace",
                "Scientific exploration"
            ],
            "answer": "Greed and pride",
            "id": 254
        },
        {
            "question": "In the context of the Fox Wars, who were the 'western allies' mentioned?",
            "options": [
                "British forces",
                "Other Indigenous nations allied with the French",
                "Spanish colonies",
                "Dutch traders"
            ],
            "answer": "Other Indigenous nations allied with the French",
            "id": 255
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the term 'Pays d\u2019en Haut' refer to?",
            "options": [
                "The Appalachian Mountains",
                "The upper Mississippi valley",
                "The Great Lakes region",
                "The Ohio Valley"
            ],
            "answer": "The Great Lakes region",
            "id": 256
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the French approach to the remaining Foxes indicate about their colonial policies?",
            "options": [
                "They were based on assimilation",
                "They were genocidal in nature",
                "They focused on trade partnerships",
                "They emphasized religious conversion"
            ],
            "answer": "They were genocidal in nature",
            "id": 257
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the Wendat's relation to the Meskwaki, according to the text?",
            "options": [
                "They were trade partners",
                "They displaced them from southern Ontario",
                "They were allied against the French",
                "They were indifferent to the Meskwaki"
            ],
            "answer": "They displaced them from southern Ontario",
            "id": 258
        },
        {
            "question": "The French used their Indigenous allies to achieve what outcome against the Foxes?",
            "options": [
                "Ensure their trade monopoly",
                "Extinguish the Fox nation",
                "Negotiate a lasting peace",
                "Convert the Foxes to Christianity"
            ],
            "answer": "Extinguish the Fox nation",
            "id": 259
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the consequence for the Virginian colonists' interest in the Ohio Valley at the time of the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "It was encouraged by the French",
                "It led to immediate conflict with the French",
                "It highlighted the weakness of the French position",
                "It showed the strength of the French position"
            ],
            "answer": "It showed the strength of the French position",
            "id": 260
        },
        {
            "question": "Which Indigenous nations were positioned to the west of the Council of Three Fires?",
            "options": [
                "The Sioux",
                "The Meskwaki",
                "The British colonies",
                "The French outposts"
            ],
            "answer": "The Sioux",
            "id": 261
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the French's ultimate goal in the Fox Wars according to Beauharnois's biographer?",
            "options": [
                "Expansion of trade",
                "Total extermination of the Fox nation",
                "Conversion of the Indigenous peoples",
                "Establishing new colonies"
            ],
            "answer": "Total extermination of the Fox nation",
            "id": 262
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the role of gifts in the alliances between the French and Indigenous nations?",
            "options": [
                "They were ceremonial tokens",
                "They were part of wedding customs",
                "They maintained alliances",
                "They were tributes of submission"
            ],
            "answer": "They maintained alliances",
            "id": 263
        },
        {
            "question": "What was the Meskwaki's position in the trade between the Council of Three Fires and the Sioux nations?",
            "options": [
                "They were competitors",
                "They were the primary traders",
                "They were intermediaries",
                "They were excluded from trade"
            ],
            "answer": "They were intermediaries",
            "id": 264
        },
        {
            "question": "What European country's colonists were considering expansion into the Ohio Valley during the Fox Wars?",
            "options": [
                "France",
                "Spain",
                "England",
                "The Netherlands"
            ],
            "answer": "England",
            "id": 265
        },
        {
            "question": "What action by the French demonstrated their approach to diplomacy with Indigenous nations?",
            "options": [
                "Sending ambassadors",
                "Establishing trade schools",
                "Gift-giving to maintain alliances",
                "Building fortifications"
            ],
            "answer": "Gift-giving to maintain alliances",
            "id": 266
        }
    ]
}